# **BAKARE ABIMBOLA SOPHIA**

28, Olu-Aina Street, Off Isolo Road, Mushin, Lagos. 08092592480 | deomolara@yahoo.com

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Meticulous and innovative front-end developer with 2 years of front end development and passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. I am seeking to obtain a creative and challenging position where I can enhance my skillset in web technologies to develop and implement solutions to meet business needs. Experienced in developing web page effectively using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, Vue.JS that are cross-browser compatible.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Tech Studio Academy.

Sept 2019- February 2020

- Full-stack web development.
- o Acquired in-depth knowledge in frontend web development languages such as HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Furthered knowledge base and experience in Backend web development in node.JS and Databases (SQL).
- o Created websites that are user-friendly, effective and appealing.

W3Schools. July 2018-July 2019

- Front-end web development.
- Acquired in-depth knowledge in frontend web development languages such as HTML,
  CSS, and JavaScript.
- o Learnt how to create responsive and mobile-friendly web pages.

# University of Lagos, Akoka. 2013-2017

• Physics Education (Bsc.Ed.)

#### **SKILLS AND ABILITIES**

- HTML5, CSS3
- Bootstrap, Material UI and similar UI libraries
- JavaScript, React, Redux, Vue.JS
- Version Control Git
- Responsive design and mobile-first web applications
- Highly innovative.
- Demonstrated ability to follow instructions and multitask.
- Proven written, oral communication, and interpersonal skills.

#### **GITHUB LINK**

• https://www.github.com/AbimbolaBakare

#### PORTFOLIO LINK

• https://abimbola-bakare.netlify.app

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **DuroNetworks – GETRIPAY** Frontend Engineer

July 2020 – Date

Getripay is a subset of DuroNetworks that creates financial solutions for users. It has the features of bank transfers, bill payments like utility bills, cable TV, airtime, etc., loan and many others. As the front-end developer, my core activities include:

- Developing unique user experiences that drives interaction, using JavaScript (React), from scratch.
  - Building the user interface for a financial technology application (FIN-TECH) from concept through deployment, with a responsive, mobile-first approach.
  - Build reusable code and libraries for future use.
  - Ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs.
  - Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability.
  - Assure that all user input is validated before submitting to back-end.
  - Collaborated with team members to implement new feature developments.
  - Participating in code reviews

# Grandilo Technology Web Development Intern

Dec 2019 – March 2020

- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.JS, Firebase, Postman, API for developing dynamic single page application.
- Developed, enhanced, maintained the front end functionality of websites.
- Applied media queries to create responsive website across different size of screens.
- Involved in using GIT, for project management and version management.
- Implemented FIREBASE as a storage for a study abroad website.
- Used axios to call APIs and postman for testing of the APIs.
- Built a travel agency website.

## Cloud-Soft Systems Network Nigeria Intern Website Developer

- Dec 2017 Feb 2018
- Built and uploaded functioning websites using WordPress.
- Successfully built and published over 4 websites, for a diverse range of clients. Used CSS extensively in the development of website.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- NYSC- National Youth Service Corps Certificate (2019)
- New Horizons- Diploma in Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) (2019)
- New Horizons- Diploma in CompTIA A+ (Computer Engineering) (2019)
- Tech Studio Academy (Full Stack Web development) (2020)

#### **INTERESTS**

• Reading, technology and learning new skills.

### • REFERENCES

Available on request.